<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data-Platforms on ftisiot ideas about tech, food and life</title>
    <link>https://ftisiot.net/categories/data-platforms/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data-Platforms on ftisiot ideas about tech, food and life</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 09:10:21 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ftisiot.net/categories/data-platforms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SOFT Methodology</title>
      <link>https://ftisiot.net/soft/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 09:10:21 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ftisiot.net/soft/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This page contains all the links related to the SOFT (Scalable Observable Fast Trustworthy) methodology for defining robust data platforms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What are the directions of technical data platforms scalability?</title>
      <link>https://ftisiot.net/posts/tech-scalability/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 09:14:26 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ftisiot.net/posts/tech-scalability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Technical scalability is one of the main drivers of a data platform, as mentioned in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://aiven.io/blog/a-soft-methodology-to-define-robust-data-platforms&#34;&gt;SOFT methodology&lt;/a&gt;. But what are the options? In this blog we&amp;rsquo;ll evaluate the direction of scalability and the tradeoffs you might encounter in the decision process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From data stack to data stuck: the risks of not asking the right data questions</title>
      <link>https://ftisiot.net/posts/from-data-stack-to-data-stuck/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 11:35:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ftisiot.net/posts/from-data-stack-to-data-stuck/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Companies are in a continuous motion: new requirements, new data streams, new technologies are popping up every day. When designing new data platforms supporting the needs of your company, failing to perform a complete assessment of the options available can have disastrous effects on a company&amp;rsquo;s capability to innovate, and making sure their data assets usable and reusable in the long term.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
